以下是《无耻家庭》前情提要
This is what you missed last week on Shameless.
我还没爽完呢
I'm not finished yet.
弗朗西斯·加拉格  你愿意娶我吗
Francis Gallagher, will you marry me?
我只需要一纸婚书了
All I need is a marriage certificate.
我要当你妈妈了
I'm gonna be your-- your new mom.
-真的吗  -等你老爸出狱后
- Really? - What's your dad gonna do
我告诉他你每天
when he gets out of jail and I tell him
都忙着跟人搞基
you spend all day with orange boy
你觉得他会怎么做  明天给我五百块
rubbing your dicks together? $500 tomorrow,
不然我就打给他
or I call him.
我的意思是
I try to make a point
我不能搞我室友的马子
of not banging my roommate's girlfriend.
那你又为什么在上课之前还过来这里一趟
Why'd you stop by here before class?
是因为你希望我在这里
Because you were hoping I'd be here.
-我叫邦妮  -卡尔
- I'm Bonnie. - Carl.
想不想找点乐子  把收银机里的钱都交出来
You wanna have some fun? Empty the register!
我操
Whoa, shit!
我去
Holy fuck.
恭喜啊  老兄  酒水算店里请
Congratulations, man. Drink on the house.
-为什么  -庆祝你家孩子的出生啊
- What for? - The birth of your child?
没错  我家孩子最近也出生了
Yeah, my kid just popped out too.
不过我岳母不肯让我来抚养他
But my mother-in-law won't let me raise him.
-我不是要死的人  -我只想尽量
- I'm not dying. - I'm just trying to make you
让你舒适一点
as comfortable as possible.
那就带我去艾莱柏
Then take me to the Alibi.
快过来  弗兰克
Get your ass down here, Frank.
-搞什么  -没法带你去酒吧
- What is this? - Couldn't bring you to the bar,
所以就把酒吧给你搬来了
so we brought the bar to you.
-我需要把枪  -你想毙了谁
- I need a gun. - Who you gonna kill?
给我把枪
Just give me a gun.
你在城南开酒吧
You own a bar on the south side.
你他妈居然没有枪
How the fuck do you not have a gun?
你可以在早八点到晚六点之间出门
You're allowed to be out 8 a.m. To 6:00 p.m.
如果你错过宵禁
If you miss curfew,
你就违反了假释的条件
you'll violate the terms of your probation,
你就回到监狱去
and you can go back to jail.
-你有工作吗  -正在找
- You got a job? - I'm working on it.
你是否有过犯罪记录
Have you ever been convicted of a felony?
我们再联系吧
You know, we will be in touch.
你以为自己是个好人
You think that you're good person.
-但你不是  -我的人生全毁了就因为你
- You're not. - Everything is fucked because of you!
无耻家庭
第四季第十集
■
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译：  扎克不渣     重案组李Sir     ztonyy     君君
■
翻译：  青椒     爱卿遛小鸟     猛回头     Greentie
时间轴：  信徒     浓子     芝麻圆子
■
校对：  Greentie      落
后期： 孤帆          总监： 落
■
卡尔
Carl...
这将是你和爸的
These are the last words that will pass
最后一次对话了
between you and your father,
把你以前一直想对他说
your chance to put everything
却没机会说出来的
you've ever wanted to say to Frank
就当着这最后的机会全说了吧
into one final talk.
你会永生铭记这一刻的
You're gonna remember it for the rest of your life.
明白吗  亲爱的
All right, sweetheart?
别紧张
Now, no pressure.
你可以先酝酿一会儿
I'll give you a moment.
爸爸  你感觉怎么样
Daddy, how do you feel?
我准备好
I'm ready...
他说他已经准备好遵循主的旨意了
He said he's ready for the lord's will.
我准备好
I'm ready...
再吃些药了
for more pills.
药啊
More pills. Um...
奥施康定都吃完了
We're out of oxys,
不过我已经叫药贩子送液态吗啡过来了
but I have a dealer coming with liquid morphine.
行吗
Okay?
卡尔
Carl, if--
Carl?
这样  你们给我准备一束花
Well, I was thinking of just, like, a bouquet,
还有给新郎准备一个别在衣领上的花束
and then a boutonniere for the groom,
以及餐桌中央的摆饰
and just maybe a centerpiece.
玫瑰呀  那再好不过了
Oh, roses. That would be really nice.
好啊  你能给我一个报价吗
Yeah, can you get me a quote on that?
好的  谢谢
Okay, thank you.
觉得怎么样  我做了点修改
What do you think? I had it altered.
我还问了恰奇他愿不愿意当花童
And I asked Chuckie if he wanted to be the ring bearer,
他说他愿意
and he said yes.
我觉得他为此挺高兴的
And I think he's excited.
虽然
Although...
我也不太能确定那是不是高兴的表情
it's kind of hard to tell with him.
希拉
Oh, Sheila.
弗兰克恐怕熬不到你的婚礼了
Frank isn't gonna make it to your wedding.
虽然这主意真的很不错
It was a lovely idea,
但他现在所需要的就是平静安详地离去
but what he needs now is just to die in peace.
请你别再说下去了好吗
Can you stop saying that?
放手也可以是一件很美好的事
Letting go can be a beautiful thing.
这么跟你说吧  我本来对婚礼的事
You know what? I'm kind of excited
还挺兴奋的
about my marriage,
可你现在这套"你的未婚夫就要归西了"的说辞
and you're kind of being a downer
还真是有够扫兴的
with this whole "Your fiance's gonna die" thing.
所以我给他做了清肝排毒餐
So I made him a liver cleanse.
这里面有蛋白和泡菜汁
It's got egg whites and pickle juice.
美国一档关于健康养生的电视真人秀节目
我从《奥兹医生》里学来的
I saw it on Dr. Oz.
总之  这些对补充电解质很有益处
Anyway, it's really, really good for the electrolytes.
他无法吞咽
He can't swallow.
这段婚姻不是为了我
This isn't about me.
而是为了五个印第安裔美国孩子
This is about five american indian children
他们无父无母
who have no parents,
要是我和弗兰克结不成婚的话
who cannot become part of this family
他们就不能合法成为这个家庭的成员
unless Frank and I are married.
印第安人的部落会议将在六天后召开
Now, the tribal council is in six days,
如果弗兰克想在那之后死去  那随他的便
and if Frank wants to die after that, it's up to him.
现在  我要去给他清肝排毒
Now, I'll be giving him his cleanse.
对了  就是这样
All right, that's it.
在下次宫缩前先休息一下
Just rest before the next contraction.
你做得很好  亲爱的
You are doing amazing, honey.
你怎么知道
How would you know?
因为别人生孩子也是这么叫的啊
Because you're making all the right sounds.
还记得咱们看过的那个生产视频吗
Remember that birthing video with the chick
里面那个女的就是发出水牛一样的叫声
making all the buffalo noises?
你现在的叫声就跟里面一样
You're totally making those noises.
-菲奥娜在哪里  -我给她留言了
- Where's Fiona? - I left a message.
八点之前她不能离开家  记得吗
She can't leave the house before 8:00, right?
她可能正赶过来呢
She's probably on her way.
你要不要站到我们这边来
Would you like to stand around here with us?
-不  不用  -你不想看吗
- No, I'm good. - You don't want to watch?
亲爱的  我上次就站那里呢
Oh, honey, I was over there earlier,
还看到了一些超重口的东西
and I saw some hardcore shit,
简直跟恐怖电影有的一拼
like, horror movie shit.
所以  我还是待在你身边比较好
No, I'm gonna stay with you.
那个
You know--
对了  对了
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
老天  我真抱歉我帮不上忙
God, I am so sorry I can't help.
在这事儿上我真是没用
I'm useless at this.
那个  汤米说在有些文化中
You know, Tommy says that in some cultures
男人压根儿不能靠近生产现场
men aren't even allowed near the birth,
就只有一堆女人待在帐篷里  这样就说得通了
just a bunch of women in tents, which makes sense,
因为我要是在追捕麋鹿什么的
because I would be so much more useful
那倒还算派上用处了
if I was out hunting moose or something.
闭嘴  别他妈说了  凯文
Shut up, shut the fuck up, Kevin.
别他妈说话了
Please shut the fuck up.
好的
Okay, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
-曼迪还在睡吗  -在利普的房间
- Hey, Mandy still asleep? - In Lip's room.
你在吃什么  煎饼吗
What are you eating, pancakes?
你几点起来的
What fucking time did you get up?
五点
5:00.
你三点才下班回来
You didn't get back from work until 3:00.
是啊  我今早去跑步了
Yeah, I went for a run this morning.
我能量爆棚
I have a ton of energy. Oh!
看看这日出
Check out this sunrise.
看啊  太美了
Look at that. It's crazy.
是啊  真的很美
Yeah, that's real nice.
玩了一宿老男人的蛋蛋
Must really clear your mind watching a sunrise
确实要看看日出净化一下
after a long night of gargling old man balls.
煎饼算我的
Pancakes are on me.
你不是破产了吗
Thought you were broke.
没有  只是有个孩子的妈
Nah, man, I just got a baby mama
要榨我的钱而已
with her fucking hand in my pocket.
我跟你说小凯要收窑子的租金了吗
I mention Kev is charging rent for the rub 'n' tug?
是不是太缺德了
How's that for bullshit?
菲奥娜没有回家
Fiona never came home.
她违反了假释条例
She violated probation.
她没在她的房间吗
She's not in her room?
我昨晚看了  今早又看了
I checked last night, again this morning.
-又要回监狱了  -我给希拉打电话了
- Back to the metal motel. - I called Sheila.
她没在  也没在医院
She's not there, and she's not at the hospital
-陪小凯和小维  -去医院干嘛
- with Kev and V-- - The hospital?
小维生孩子了
V's having her babies.
是吗  真好
She is? Wow.
菲奥娜不会故意错过宵禁的
Fiona would not miss her curfew on purpose.
她被劫了  或者掉进地铁道了怎么办
What if she got mugged or fell in front of the El?
她没事的  小黛
She's probably fine, Debs.
她可能获得许可出门了
Maybe she got permission to go out.
你觉得我们要报警吗
You don't think we should call the police?
不  后果只会更严重
No, that'll just make shit worse.
那我们怎么办
Well, then what do we do?
我上学的时候
Will someone at least call hospitals
-能不能打电话去医院问问  -交给我吧
- While I'm at school? - I'm on it.
卡尔给我做的小刀让我弄丢了
Ugh, I lost the shiv Carl made for me.
融化了的牙刷  胶带手柄
Melted toothbrush, duct tape handle--
你要小刀干嘛
Why do you need a shiv?
以防我遇到前男友的新女友
In case I run into my ex-boyfriend's new girlfriend.
你怎么了
What--what happened to you?
-肯亚塔揍的  -我没事了  好吗
- Kenyatta happened. - I'm over it, okay?
别说了
Let's move on.
我跟米奇说她可以待在这
I told Mickey she could stay here.
你不能回去
And you're not going back, by the way.
我们会给你安排住的地方  好吗
We'll find you someplace to live, okay?
她凭啥走  那是我们的房子
Fuck should she leave? It's our house.
你为什么反应这么大
Why are you making such a big deal about it?
-烦死了  -我得走了
- Jesus. - I have to go.
你会打电话到医院吗
Are you calling hospitals?
会的  现在就打
Yep. Sorry. Doing it now.
找到了
Oh, there it is.
-那个是小刀吗  -是的  回见
- That a shiv? - Yep. Later.
刚13岁  就带小刀上学了
13 years old, she's bringing a shiv to class.
太怀念高中了
Man, I miss high school.
嘿  小朋友
Hey. Hey, little man.
考得怎么样
How'd it go?
我提前答完了
I finished early,
还检查了一遍
double-checked my answers.
谁知道会考成啥样
Who the hell knows?
你看上去不怎么开心
You don't look happy.
黛比给我发短信了
Well, Debbie texted,
说菲奥娜昨晚没有回家
and, uh, Fiona didn't come home last night.
鉴于她正处在假释阶段
And since she's under house arrest,
所以是个大问题
that's kind of a problem.
但是你帮不到
Ouch. But there's not really
什么忙  对吧
anything you can do, is there?
打几个电话  看看能不能
Uh, make some calls, uh, try to figure out
找到她
where she is, uh--
是啊  我不知道我们能做什么
Yeah, I don't really know what we can do.
你能专心复习
Well, are you able to stay focused
-准备考试吗  -我能
- on your exams? - Yes, I am focused.
这是什么
What's this?
你期中考试的日程表
A laminated schedule of your midterms
大概算了一下你需要考多少分才能拿到B
and a sliding scale of the scores you need
以保住你的奖学金
to get a "B" And keep your scholarship.
厉害
Holy shit.
今晚见
Well, I'll see you tonight.
没准儿可以来个69
Maybe we'll 69.
他能听见吗
Uh, look, can he hear us?
库兹勒  你能听见我跟利普说
Hey, Kuzner, you hear what I said to Lip
我要坐在他的脸上给他吹箫吗
about sitting on his face while I bob for knob?
他听不见
He can't hear us.
好吧  晚点见
Um, okay, I'll catch you later, yeah?
我能听见
I can hear.
亲爱的  这些糖是为
Oh, sweetie, that's-- that's candy
婚礼礼袋准备的
for the gift bags for the wedding.
-我能吃糖吗  -亲爱的  别打扰
- Can I have candy? - Sweetie, let mommy do
妈妈做毒品交易  宝贝
her drug deal, honey.
我们有维柯丁
We got vicodin...
氢吗啡酮  芬太尼
Dilaudid, and duragesic.
-液态吗啡有吗  -200刀
- Liquid morphine? - Two hundy.
-奥施康定  -每只20刀
- Oxys? - 20 each.
可待因呢  我爸的肝衰竭了
Codeine? Dad's liver's failing.
他很痛苦
He's in a lot of pain.
那得两万五美元
That's gonna cost about 25 grand.
-可待因吗  -新的肝
- For codeine? - For a new liver.
不是你说的嘛
What--isn't that what you just said?
等等  我糊涂了
W-wait, wait. I'm confused.
你能做肝脏移植
You do liver transplants?
不不  但是我认识一个人
No. No, no, no. But I know a guy.
做一些秘密的手术
Kind of works on the down-low.
不好意思
I-I-I wa-- I wa--I'm sorry.
我不小心听到
I was just eavesdropping.
你是说两万五美元
Did you just say that you do a liver
就可以做一个肝移植
and a transplant for $25,000?
是的  是这样的
Sure, last I checked.
你有医疗记录是吧
But you do have medical records, right?
我认识的那个人需要用记录找到配型
My boy needs that to find a match.
我们能给弗兰克买个肝
We can buy Frank a liver!
给我们点时间 好吗
Give us a sec.OK?
-我有点存款  -好的
- I have-- a little money saved. - Yeah.
你把我的家具卖了
And you had to have made some money
肯定也赚了点钱
from selling off my furniture.
家具都用塑料套着
I mean, that was covered in plastic...
-好的  -没有瑕疵
- Okay. - and pristine.
好的  不要太激动
- Okay, but before we get too excited,
移植手术  是个大手术
A transplant--that's a major medical procedure.
-是的  -这个人是我
- Yes. - This guy is a dealer
在演唱会停车场上遇见的药贩子
I met in a parking lot after a Phish concert.
好的
Okay.
他卖给你坏药了吗
Did he sell you bad drugs?
没有
No.
-他是个种梨的农民  -什么
- He's a pear farmer. - What?
艾弗里  我们在威斯康星州的朋友
Avery, our friend in Wisconsin.
他的农场都是有机的
His farm is totally organic.
施的堆肥  天然的防虫液
Compost, natural bug repellent.
我们都轮班耕种  在收获的季节  我们
We all take shifts, and during harvest season, we--
伙计  这是什么
Dude, what, uh, what is this?
是个脚踝监控器吗
Huh? Is this an ankle monitor?
-是她的  -什么
- Hers. - Huh?
它响了
It's beeping, dude.
那就是说警察会来找它
That means the cops are gonna come looking for it.
那你为什么还拿着
So why are you still holding it?
-扔外面去  -你觉得里面有定位器吗
- Chuck it outside. - Do you think it's got GPS?
在夜晚  你抬头可以看到银河
At night, you look up and can see the milky way,
白色的  像牛奶一样
And it's all white and... Milky, hee-hee.
那颗摇头丸怎么样
Hey, how about that ecstasy?
不用了  谢谢
No, thanks.
你已经吃了
You already took it.
嗨翻了吧
It feels nice, right?
今天留堂的时候你特别安静
You were quiet today in detention.
我不太想谈这个
I don't really want to talk about it.
好吧
Okay.
我爸快死了
My dad's dying.
好事还是坏事
Is that a good thing or a bad thing?
总的来说算坏事吧
Mostly bad.
那我找个办法让你忘了这件事
Well, let's do something to take your mind off of it.
比如说
Like what?
99年款的福特康图尔  好偷得很
This is a '99 ford contour. They're pretty easy.
我们这是在偷车吗
Are we stealing it?
把点火缸剥出来  再连几根电线
Just have to expose the ignition cylinder, cross some wires.
-你能教我我吗  -快上车
- Can you teach me? - Get in.
老天哪  真是太好了
Oh, lord. Oh, how wonderful.
快来见见你的外甥姐妹
Ready to meet your sister nieces?
她们可想见你啦
They've been asking about you.
瞧瞧她们多可爱啊
Ooh, aren't they perfect?
护士把她们扔这儿就走了
The nurses just left 'em here,
好像我们多会带孩子似的
like we know what the fuck we're doing.
这位是艾米  那位是杰玛
This is Amy, and that's Jemma.
小凯居然想给她取名叫扎尼夸
Kev wanted to name her Zaniqua.
一个正常名字  一个伪非洲风情名字
Well, you know, one pseudo-african name, one normal one.
宝贝  看看手机
Babe, check that.
只是凯特发过来的祝福短信
No, it's just Kate saying congratulations.
怎么了
Well, what-- what's wrong?
菲奥娜一直没来
Fiona never showed up,
小凯打电话问利普
and then Kev called Lip, and he said
他说他昨天整晚都没回家
She never came home last night.
她还在假释期内呢
You know she's under house arrest.
这可有点糟糕
Oh, that's not good.
我去买点婴儿湿巾和婴儿湿疹膏
You know I gotta go pick up baby wipes and rash cream.
顺便再打听打听菲奥娜到底去哪儿了
Yeah, I'll go ask around, see what's up with Fiona.
加拉格家和希拉家都去找找看
Go by the Gallaghers'. Go by Sheila's.
酒吧我也会去看看的
And I'll stop by the alibi too.
再来教我认认
All right, now, uh, tell me again.
这个是艾米对吧
Um, this one's Amy.
应该是吧  我记得住她们名字
Uh, I think so. I mean, I know their names.
只是有点分不清谁是谁
I'm just not 100% yet on which one is which.
这几家医院我们都打去问过了
We called these hospitals, but they all said
他们都说没有收治一个名叫菲奥娜的病人
Fiona's not a registered patient,
但是如果她失去意识了的话
but if she's unconscious,
他们也没办法知道她叫什么名字
they wouldn't have her name.
-你觉得她失去意识了  -我可没说
- You think she's unconscious? - No.
我也不知道  你一家一家的问问看
I don't know, just call and tell them you need to look
看看他们昨天收治的病人当中
at all the patients admitted yesterday
有没有人像菲奥娜
who match Fiona's description.
我上班要迟到啦
I'm late for work.
你刚刚那段话太长了  记不住
I might not remember all that.
放心  我给你写下来了
Well, that's why I wrote it down.
行  我得走了  邦尼在等我
Cool, I gotta go. Bonnie's waiting.
你赶得及去五家医院吗
You really think you can get to five hospitals?
她车开得很快
She drives fast.
看得出来吗
Hey, does this look okay?
-你怎么做到的  -拼命遮呗
- How did you do that? - Cover-up.
泰瑞挖掘出了我的绘画天赋
Living with Terry brought out the artist in me.
车不错
Nice wheels.
是啊  这是阿曼达的车
Oh, yeah, it's Amanda's.
她是我的...
You know, she's sort of my, uh--
我也说不清楚
I don't know.
虽然这不是我第一次被男朋友打了
It's not the first time a boyfriend's beaten the crap Out of me,
但我保证这绝对是最后一次
but it's definitely the last.
-但愿如此  -你男朋友怎么样
- I'd hope so. - How's your boyfriend?
他可不是我男朋友
Mm, he's not.
抱歉我不知道情况有变
Sorry, I lost track.
我事情太多了  根本顾不上想他
I have too much to do to even worry out him
也没空管他现在在跟谁约会
or the girl he's seeing,
所以这其实挺好的
so really, it's a good thing.
如果你以后碰见男人扇你耳光
The first guy who even slaps you,
你就拿把刀直接捅他眼睛
I want you to take that shiv and jam it in his eye.
先下手为强
Don't even let him start.
利普让我直接捅他蛋蛋
Hmm, Lip told me to go for the scrotum,
不过眼睛也不错
but the eye works too.
你们看没看见有个未成年少女
Did anyone just see an underage girl
开着车把卡尔载走了
drive off in a beater with Carl?
-那是邦尼  -邦尼是谁
- Yeah, that would be Bonnie. - Who the fuck's Bonnie?
你怎么来了
Hey. What, uh, what brings you here?
她过来住是因为肯亚塔
She's staying with us because Kenyatta--
不用告诉他这些细节
You can spare him the details.
只是暂住  所以你这阵子可得收敛点哦
It's temporary, so don't get your flowered panties in a knot.
-你的眼睛怎么了  -操蛋了呗
- What happened to your eye? - This.
-好吧  -专门把利亚姆送回来吗
- Okay. - Ah, you dropping Liam off?
我过几个小时有场考试
Yeah, yeah, I got an exam in a few hours.
有菲奥娜的消息了没
Any word on fiona?
卡尔和伊恩去医院里找了
Uh, Carl and Ian are checking hospitals,
我一会儿再打给小凯问问看
but I'll try Kev again later.
我已经问过他了  他也不知道
No, I already talked to him. He's got nothing.
菲奥娜脚踝上不是有个监视器吗
Doesn't Fiona have an ankle monitor?
我们干嘛不让保释局帮我们
Can't we just call the probation officer
找找看她在哪里
and see if they know where she is?
不能让他们知道菲奥娜
No, we don't want to draw their attention
失踪了这件事情
to the fact that she's gone awol.
可万一她受伤了  或者被绑架了
But if she's hurt or-- or kidnapped--
如果实在找不到她
Look, if we don't find her soon,
我们再采取这个办法  好吗
we'll consider that option, okay?
我这辈子尽找人了
All I do is look for my family.
最好给你们每个人都装个监视器
I'm getting all of you ankle monitors.
怎么  打算在我们皮肤底下种植芯片么
What, lojack chips under the skin?
我可没跟你开玩笑
I'm not kidding.
我们现在该怎么办  拿着玩
So what do we do now? Here, you go, baby.
等着
Well, we wait.
祈祷她没事
Hope she's okay.
你能给他做点午饭么  我得看书
Hey, will you, uh, make him some lunch? I need to study.
没问题
Yeah.
想吃午饭吗
Wanna go get lunch?
-谢了  -肚子饿吗
- Thanks. - Hungry?
别碰那个
Ooh, no, no, no. Don't touch that.
您叫什么名字呀
What did you say your name was again?
我不会透露我的真名的
I prefer not to use my real name.
你们就叫我强尼吧
If you like, you can call me "Johnny."
我是一名外科医生
I'm a trained surgeon with a medical degree
孟加拉吉大港正经医学院毕业
from Chittagong, Bangladesh.
我只是没有美国的行医执照而已
I'm just not licensed in this country.
没关系  孟加拉国的执照好歹也是执照
Well, as long as you're licensed somewhere.
你们哪儿来的肝源
Where will you get the liver?
根据你们提供的医疗信息
I've already secured a donor
我已经找到了一个可靠的捐赠者
based on the medical records you provided.
我们团队有专业的麻醉医生  肝病专家
I have an anesthesiologist, hepatologist,
外科医生  医疗设备也很齐全
surgical staff, and facilities with the necessary equipment.
但是我们不会负责病人的康复阶段
But we will not oversee the patient's recovery.
移植手术之后  你们就把他送去医院
After the transplant, you take him to the hospital.
到时候急诊室会收治他的
The ER will admit him that point,
他们不会追问肝的来源
regardless of how we got the liver.
你们什么时候想开始手术
When did you say you want to do the procedure?
越快越好
As soon as possible.
明天不行
O-only not tomorrow,
明天的行程已经都排满了
'cause tomorrow's already pretty full.
我们要结婚
We're getting married.
恭喜
Congratulations.
谢谢
Thank you.
移植手术需要花费两万五千美元
The transplant will cost 25,000 american dollars,
肝需要另付五千
plus 5,000 for the liver--
加起来一共是三万美元
30,000 in total.
两万六  干不干
Can you do it for 26,000 total?
我们只有这么多
That's all we've got.
我们就...这么多
That, uh, that's what we--
因为之前...听说是
We were told that-- that--
成交
I will accept this offer.
他就是你们的捐赠者
That is your liver.
沙卡瓦特的匹配度很高
Shakhawat is a perfect match.
他会捐献一片肝叶
He will give you one lobe.
谢谢  你真好
Thank you. That-that is so nice of you.
谢谢
Thanks.
打这个号码联系我
Contact me at this number.
失陪了
Now excuse me.
的士还在等我
I have a taxi waiting.
再说一遍你叫什么来着
What did you say your name was again?
是的
Yes.
没找到她
There's no sign of her.
为什么我们家都没人学过弹吉他
Hey, how come none of us ever learned to play guitar?
或者演奏任何乐器
Or any instrument?
我在想  也许我们该去学学吉他
I was thinking that maybe we could pick up guitar
或是钢琴  甚至是鼓
or--or piano, or drums even, just--
演奏乐器是一个很好的自我表达的方式
It--it's such a cool way to express yourself,
罗斯福大道有群街头音乐家
'cause it--there were these street musicians on Roosevelt,
他们经常在街上演奏...
and they had this groove thing going, and--
听起来有趣极了
That sounds really interesting,
但我正试着学习德国哲学呢
But I'm trying to read german philosophy.
行吗  心情好的时候学这个就已经够难的了
Okay? Which is hard enough on a good day,
那时候我不用想象菲奥娜已经死在
meaning a day when I'm not imagining Fiona dead
某道沟渠里了
in a ditch somewhere,
所以你能不能...
so if you could just please--
抱歉
Sorry.
对不起  小黛
I'm sorry, Debs.
我得走了
I gotta go.
菲奥娜不在家
Just 'cause Fiona's gone
不代表她出事了
Doesn't mean she's hurt.
我参军时
I mean, when I joined the army,
只不过是想离开一阵子
I just needed to get away for a little while.
如果她跟弗兰克一样怎么办
What if she's pulling a Frank?
什么意思
What do you mean?
她到了某个地方
Well, she went somewhere
搞得一团糟
and got fucked up.
那不像是菲奥娜的作风
It's not like Fiona.
她这个月所做的事有哪一件像是她的作风
And what has she done this month that is like Fiona?
最近几天
I mean, these past few days,
她心情都很低落
she's been pretty down.
我们对她的态度都很差
We've been kinda hard on her.
怎么  还是我们的错了
What, so it's our fault?
我没这么说
I didn't say that.
我一直在故意无视她
I've been pretty much ignoring her.
别说了  好吗  别这么想
Stop. Okay? Don't go down that road.
她跌到谷底  那是她自己的问题
If she's bottoming out, that's on her.
我们就跟以前找弗兰克一样
So we act like we're looking for Frank.
去桥洞里找
Check under bridges.
对  为什么不呢
Yeah, why not?
市监狱有醉汉监禁室
There's a drunk tank at the city jail.
她还会跟谁混在一起
Who else would she get fucked up with?
会不会是麦克的哥哥罗比
What about Mike's brother, Robbie,
给她可卡因的那个人
the one who gave her the coke?
有可能  你有他电话吗
Yeah, you have his number?
伊恩可以给全球杯公司打电话  就说是他的老友
Ian could call worldwide cup and say he's an old friend.
很好  很好
Good. Good.
妈的  我得走了
Shit, um, look, I gotta go.
我也想留下帮忙
Um, you know, I wish I could stay and help.
但我有场考试
I just got this exam-
行了  我们懂
Yeah, whatever, we know.
请帮我查芝加哥
The number's in Chicago.
全球杯公司的号码
for worldwide cup.
今晚我睡沙发
I get the couch tonight.
在罗比家和不知名姑娘家我都睡了地板
I was on the floor at Robbie's and what's-her-name's.
行吧  那我跟艾弗里睡
Fine, I'll crash with Avery.
我要吐了
I'm gonna puke.
她刚是说要吐了吗
Did she say she's gonna puke?
那窗开不了的
Hey, that doesn't open.
不能吐车里  好吗
Do not puke in the van, okay?
-靠边停车  -这里不能
- Pull over. - Yeah, but I can't
-靠边停车  -她要...
- Pull over here. - Oh, she's--
天呐
Oh, god.
太恶心了
Oh, damn.
让她坐好
Get her back in.
我们在哪
Where are we?
在车里
In the van.
你不是讨厌艾弗里吗
I thought you hated Avery.
我们要去哪
Where are we going?
就那一次
That was one time.
我昏过去了
I was passed out.
艾弗里上了我
Avery had sex with me.
-我们要去哪  -那挺不厚道的
- Where are we going? - That was not cool.
但平时  他人还是挺好的
But usually, he's, like, a pretty cool guy.
刚刚说到哪了  对了
Okay, so where were we? Right.
来看看
So let's see.
婚鞋
Shoes.
你觉得怎么样
What are you thinking here?
鱼嘴鞋
Open-toe...
还是包头鞋
Or...Closed?
包头鞋
真的吗
Really?
我喜欢这款设计  因为减去冗杂  线条简单
真有意思
That's so interesting.
好的  我觉得我们可能想法是一致的
Okay, 'cause I think we might be on the same page here.
请帖用亮面的还是磨砂的
Glossy or matte program?
萨咪
Sammi.
失去
Loss...
是生命循环的一部分
Is part of the cycle of life.
万物都会衰败
Whatever g-grows must decay.
没什么是永恒的
Everything is temporary,
而你  希拉  非常勇敢
and--and you,You, Sheila, are so brave.
谢谢你
Thank you.
不过你到底在说什么
Okay, what are we talking about, though?
我听到了死前的喉鸣
I heard the death rattle.
我检查了他的脉搏
I checked his pulse.
我打开了窗
I opened the window.
释放了他的灵魂
And I set his spirit free.
弗兰克
Frank is--
弗兰克死了
Frank is dead.
不不
No! No.
不  他没死  妈的
No, he isn't. God damn it.
-别把窗关上  -不
- Don't close the window! - Oh, no.
你不希望我关窗的
You don't want me to close the window.
-他的灵魂...  - 弗兰克
- His spirit- - Frank!
弗兰克  弗兰克
Frank! Frank.
把头抬起来
Okay, lift the head.
下巴倾斜  检查呼吸
Tilt the chin. Check for breathing.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
心肺复苏  我学过
Cpr. I learned it at the "Y".
希拉  不要  他已经走了
Sheila, no, he's already gone.
别再喊了  我听不到他有没有呼吸了
Please stop yelling. I can't hear if he's breathing.
一  二  三...
One, two, three-
别碰他的尸体
Leave his body alone!
-尸体是神圣的  -让我做心肺复苏
- This is sacred! - Please let me do this!
住手
Stop!
我勒个大操
For fuck's sake.
爸  天呐  谢天谢地
Dad? Oh, my god. Oh, thank god.
我刚确信他已经死了
I thought for sure he was already gone.
好了  够了
All right, that's it.
我们要打给那个的士司机医生
We are calling the taxi-driving doctor.
我们要给他换肝
And we are doing this transplant...
-放走干吧  -现在就打
- Let's do this. - Right now.
到你上场了  先生
You're up, mister!
还有弗兰克  如果你死了
And, Frank, if you die,
我真的会很失望的
I will be really disappointed.
的士司...  的士...
Taxi d--taxi--
我就知道你在家
I knew you were home.
什么
What?
我们按门铃已经按了20分钟了
We've been ringing the bell for 20 minutes.
我刚在睡觉
Okay, I was asleep.
菲奥娜在吗
Is Fiona here?
你是哪位
Do I know you?
那是她的鞋
Those are her shoes!
你能叫一下菲奥娜吗
Would you please get Fiona?
就说黛比和伊恩来了
Tell her Debbie and Ian are here.
行了  你等等
Okay, just--just hold on.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我昨天试了几个杠铃练习
Oh, I tried these barbell lift exercises.
真的很锻炼肩膀
They really work your shoulders.
她来过这里
She was here.
应该已经走了
I-I guess she left.
因为大家都走了
Because everybody left.
她不穿鞋  不穿外套  不拿手机就走了
She left without her shoes, her coat, or her phone?
真的吗
Really?
应该吧
Guess so, yeah.
她什么时候走的
Well, when did she leave?
跟谁一起走的
Did she go with anyone?
有没有说去哪里
Did she say where she was going?
-我也不清楚  -菲奥娜
- I mean, I, maybe-- - Fiona!
菲奥娜
Fiona!
求别吼
Don't do that.
从现在起  你离她远点
From now on, stay away from her.
-听懂了吗  -好吧
- Understand? - Okay.
得通知利普
Better tell Lip.
女士们  先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
我们家有了两位新成员
announcing the latest addition to the ball family,
艾米和杰玛
Amy and Jemma!
恭喜啊
Yeah, attaboy!
真棒
Proud papa.
就给点香烟
Cigarettes?
你知道现在的香烟加上税有多贵吗
You know how much cigarettes are with tax?
跟雪茄价格差不多了
What cigars used to be.
那酒呢
What about drinks?
请全场免费喝
Drinks for everyone.
这才像话
Attaboy.
谢谢
Thanks!
每人一杯  半杯加冰  只给普通酒
One each, half off, well drinks only.
他要是生了三胞胎会怎样
Imagine if he had triplets.
我们就有免费冰块了
We'd get free ice.
你们少来了  生了宝宝要花很多钱的
Yeah, yeah, well,I got a lot of baby-related expenses.
帕科  这他妈怎么回事
Paco, what the fuck is this?
问你的搭档去
Talk to your business partner.
欢迎下次光临
Yeah, come again.
你跟这些人说一下  他妈的穿这么多
Hey, can you tell these girls to show a little skin,
给老子露点肉
for christ's sake?
又不是要爬珠穆朗玛峰
They're not climbing Everest.
就几根鸡巴而已
They're climbing dick.
这里很冷
It's cold.
有暖气
There's heat.
在楼下
Downstairs.
热气会上升
And heat rises.
会透过地板传上来  你看
It comes up through the floor. Look at this.
你好啊  来自北极的北极熊
Hey, nanook of the fuckin' north,
把你那件皮大衣脱了
why don't you lose the parka,
又不是让你跟爱斯基摩人上床
unless you're planning on banging Eskimos?
米奇  今天我孩子出生
Mickey, the day my babies are born,
你居然把收银台里的钱都掳走了
you steal cash from the register?
收银台是你的
Yeah, your register.
钱是我的
My cash.
又不止你一个人要烦孩子的破事
I'm not the only sap that gets saddled with a kid around here.
你他妈还穿什么衣服
Why the fuck are you wearing clothes?
凭什么是你的钱
How is it your cash?
因为上周的钱你还没全给我
'Cause you still owe me from last week.
再说还有中介费用
Plus now there's a finder's fee.
什么
A what?
中介费
Finder's fee.
你要收租金
You're gonna charge for rent,
我也要收妓女们的钱  20%
I'm gonna charge for whores, 20%.
-放屁  -这就像那个...
- Bullshit. - No. It's like, uh,
什么来着
What is it?
[妓女电话订购网站]
凯利女孩
Kelly girls.
只不过不是凯利  而是米奇
Instead of Kelly, it's Mickey.
也不是女孩  是妓女
Instead of girls, it's whores.
把你口袋里的钱给我
Empty your fucking pockets.
你他妈居然拿着我的枪  抢劫我
Are you robbing me with my own fucking gun?
随便你怎么说
Call it what you want.
把你口袋里的钱给我
Empty your fucking pockets.
我奉劝你一句
You better do yourself a favor
今天你最好一枪崩了我
and put a bullet in my chest,
不然的话
'cause if you don't,
你他妈就完了
you're in serious shit.
钱给我  快点
Pockets. Now.
你犯大错了
Big mistake.
失陪一下  我要去一趟沃尔玛
Now, excuse me while I go to Wal-mart
买点婴儿擦拭巾和尿疹霜
and get baby wipes and rash cream.
他死定了
He's a fucking dead man.
没消息吗
No?
我很遗憾
Sorry.
下一家医院在哪
So where to next?
这是最后一家
That was the last hospital.
那要不要开车兜兜风
Want to just drive around, then?
好
Sure.
谁教会你偷车的
Who taught you to jack cars?
我爸
My dad.
他人好吗
Is he cool?
不怎么样
Not really.
正在坐牢  因为抢了自动取款机
He's doing time for robbing ATMs.
等他出来我都30了
He won't be out till I'm 30.
你上次跟他说话是什么时候
When did you last talk to him?
四年前
Four years ago.
你说了什么
What'd you say?
什么意思
What do you mean?
就是想问你最后跟他说了什么
Like, what was the last thing you said to him?
我当时在家
I was at home,
他叫我用完海绵后
and he told me to wring out the sponge
把海绵拧干
when I was done with it,
我说好
and I said okay.
就这样吗
That's it?
当时没想到会是最后一次说话
Didn't know it was gonna be the last time.
他怎么偷的自动取款机
How'd he steal ATMs?
想看看吗
Wanna see?
有人吗
Hello?
强尼医生
Dr. Johnny?
你在吗
Hello?
强尼医生
Oh, Dr. Johnny.
你带钱了吗
You have money?
带了
Yes.
您看看
Enjoy.
萨米正在扶着弗兰克下来
Yeah, Sammy's bringing Frank down.
我们应该很快就好了
We should be ready soon.
天呐  天呐
Oh. Oh, god.
不  女士  不用你来
No, madam-- no, no, madam.
别碰  女士  你...
Don't touch. No, madam, you--
-你坐着吧  -好
- You have seat. - Okay
-好吧  -你坐着
- All right.   - You have seat.
厕所在外面
操
Shit.
操他妈的
Fuck.
我们会在腹部这里
We will make a slanting incision
做一个斜面切口
across the abdomen here,
把病变肝脏和周围脏腑分开
Separate the diseased liver from the surrounding organs,
夹住动脉和静脉...
clamp off arteries and veins--
我操他妈
我改主意了
我不管你们给多少钱
我不管  给多少  钱...
不好意思  我刚说到哪了
I'm sorry, what was I saying?
动脉什么的...
Oh, god, something about arteries and--
手术会持续六个小时
The operation will take six hours.
结束以后
When we're finished,
你们就要拨911送病人去急救室
you will call 911 and take the patient to the E.R.
时间到了
It's time.
好运  爸爸
Good luck, daddy.
我们爱你
We love you.
对  你可以挺过来的  弗兰克
Yeah, you can do this, Frank!
请出去等
Please, wait outside.
不不  这是无菌室
No no no no no, this is sterile.
绕着走  绕过去
Go around. Go around.
绕过去
Around.
手术刀
Scalpel.
列布洛维克食品酒水商店
别管自动取款机了
Forget the atm!
它们又重又难打开
They're heavy and really hard to open.
你不是说...
But I thought you-
帮我拿糖果
Just help me grab some candy.
只拿糖果吗
Just candy?
拿上这些纸杯蛋糕
Grab those cupcakes,
还有巧克力牛奶
and get chocolate milk.
多少盒
How many cartons?
能拿多少拿多少
As much as you can carry.
你真有意思
You're fun.
你知道吗
You know that?
知道  你也是
Yeah. You too.
我们该走了
We should go.
小姐  外面很冷
Miss, it's cold out.
你别在这儿坐着
I don't think you want to sit outside like this.
你  你是开车来的吗
Did--did you drive here?
有人载我来的  但他们离开了
Some...people drove me, but they left.
我能给谁打电话
Is there anyone I can call,
让他们来接你吗
someone to come and get you?
这是我的手机号
And that's-that's my cell number.
我让你姐姐听电话
Here's your sister.
嗨  利普
Hi, Lip.
我是菲奥娜
Uh, it's Fiona.
我在一个加油站
I'm at a gas station,
在希博伊根郡
in Sheboygan.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我真是一团糟
I fucked up.
我伤害了我们的弟弟  还...
I hurt our brother, and I...
违反了假释条例
fucking broke probation now.
你周璇于各种琐事
You're juggling so many things,
我还不断出岔子
and I am just fucking up.
但我现在真的需要帮助
But I need some help now.
好吗
Okay?
那位好心人把他的电话号码留给你了
So the nice man gave you the number.
谢谢
Thanks.
来吧
Here.
进来吧
Let's get you inside.
我很高兴地宣布手术成功了
I am pleased to say the operation was a success.
太棒了
Wonderful!
他还在昏迷  但没有断气
He's unconscious but breathing.
好
Okay.
请等十分钟再打911
Please wait ten minutes before calling 911,
我们可不想跟急救医生撞个正着
as we don't want to be here when the emts arrive.
到时候我们百口莫辩
It would be very hard to explain.
祝你们好运
Well, uh, good luck.
好  我们成功了  弗兰克
Okay. Oh, we did it, Frank!
你会好起来的
You're gonna be okay!
我现在就打911
I'm calling 911 now.
只有这一条毯子了
This is all I got for blankets.
要不要来点咖啡
Hey, do you want some coffee?
至少是温热的
At--at least it's warm.
我是瑞伊
This is Ray.
他问  "希博伊根郡他妈的在哪"
He asked, "where the fuck is Sheboygan?"
-小凯是朋友  -是吗
- Kev is a friend. - Yeah.
有人用我的枪指着我  把我抢了
You know, when someone robs me with my own fucking gun,
那可就不是朋友了  我就是这么一人
they're not my friend. I'm kinda funny like that.
那你想怎么样  去他家
So what are you gonna do? You're gonna go to his house,
揍他一顿吗
beat the shit out of him?
不  我要先回我家
No, I'm gonna go to my house.
带上兄弟们
I'm gonna meet up with my brothers,
再来几把带劲儿的来福枪
grab some fucking assault rifles.
然后才去他家
Then I'm going to his house.
菲奥娜在威斯康星州
Fiona's in Wisconsin.
知道  利普也给我们发短信了  笨蛋
Yeah, Lip sent us the same text too, stupid.
-她为什么会在威斯康星州  -不知道
- Why is she in Wisconsin? - I don't know.
利普说他到了会打电话回来
Lip said he'd call when he got there.
就跟你说她没事
Told you she was okay.
-我不能让你这么做  -行了  硬汉
- I'm not letting you do this. - Yeah, okay, tough guy.
米奇  你妈的拜托了
Oh, Mickey, come the fuck on.
你知道弗兰克快死了吗
You know Frank's dying.
这几年他不是都那样
He's been dying for years.
门口有辆豪车是我的
I've got a sweet set of wheels out front.
要不要搭顺风车去学校
You want a ride to school?
不要  谢了
No, thanks. Bye.
行  你跟那些挫人们一起搭巴士  吃灰去吧
Fine, ride the bus with all the other losers, and eat my dust.
有人来了
You got visitors.
那反应可真是一点都"不可疑"
At least that wasn't suspicious.
他特别害羞
Uh, heh-heh, well, he's very shy.
-早上好  -你好
- Good morning. - Hi.
我是约翰逊警官  这位是康迪基警官
I'm officer Johnson. This is officer Kandage.
-菲奥娜·加拉格在家吗  -这会儿不在
- Is Fiona Gallagher here? - Uh, not at the moment.
那她在哪
Where is she?
好像出去找工作了
I think she's out looking for a job.
你上次见到她是什么时候
When was the last time she was home?
昨晚吧  我也记不清
Last night? I'm not sure.
我和康迪基警官
Hmm, well, officer Kandage and I
要在屋里四处看看
are gonna do a little walk-through.
就几分钟  很快就走...
Just take a few minutes, and we'll be out of your--
这是什么
What's this?
织毛衣用的
I use it for knitting.
心率63次/分  不稳定
Heart rate 63 and fluctuating.
血压90/55
B.P. 90 over 55.
你感觉怎么样  弗兰克
How are you feeling, Frank?
-知道他的血型吗  -O型阳性  跟我一样
- Do you know his blood type? - "O" positive. Same as me.
病患的女儿说他最近做了肝移植手术
Uh, daughter says he recently had a liver transplant.
-有多近  -我也不知道
- How recent? - I-I don't know.
大概是...
What would you say? About--
差不多二十分钟以前吧
It was, like, 20 minutes ago?
什么二十分钟以前
What was 20 minutes ago?
肝移植手术
The transplant.
调度中心  请等一下  在哪里做的手术
Dispatch, hold on. What transplant facility?
就在刚刚那个地下室里
It's just in that basement there.
上车
Get in.
一间地下室
A basement.
恰奇  想不想搭救护车
Chuckie, want to ride in the ambulance?
不  不是医院地下室  是仓库地下室
No, not a hospital basement. Like, a warehouse.
好刺激呀
This is exciting.
好了  我要把你放下来啦
Okay, we're gonna lay you down.
好不好
Okay?
我靠
God damn it.
这是我第二次被玩乐毯绊住了
It's the second time I tripped over this play mat.
能不能换个地方摆  拜托
Can we put it somewhere else, please?
你觉得我能不能同时喂她们两个
You think I could feed them both at once?
我很乐意看你试试
I'd like to see you try.
医生说我不孕不育
The doctor said I couldn't have a baby.
现在我都成产奶机了
Now I'm gonna be a milk machine.
你和这对美胸说再见吧
You better say good-bye to these titties,
再也无法恢复曾经的尖挺了
'cause they'll never be the same again.
别这么说
Oh, do not say that. -
来  我们要把小垫子先放在下面
All right, we're gonna put your little changing mat over here.
宝贝儿
Hey, kiddo.
你在等人吗
You expecting someone?
没  我就想看看
No, I was just trying to remember
有没有把东西落在车上
if I left anything in the truck.
好了
All right.
谁准备好换尿片了呀
Who's ready for the diaper assembly line, huh?
是你吧  我会把你清理干净
I think you are. I think I have you all set.
我要把你弄得干干净净
I'm gonna get you all set.
别往妈妈身上尿尿
Don't pee pee on mommy.
我还是第一次来希博伊根呢
You know, I've never been to sheboygan before.
这里不错吧
It's nice, right?
是啊  田园风情
Yeah, it's got kind of a rural charm.
-来  -对不起
- Come here. - I'm so sorry.
没事
It's okay.
-没事的  -对不起
- It's okay. - I'm sorry.
没事的
It's okay.
你没事就好
I'm just glad you're all right.
我真的  真的很高兴
You know, I'm really, really fucking glad.
姐姐  咱们...  走吗
All right, sis, you wanna-- wanna get out of here?
那好  来
Yeah, okay. Come on.
穿上
Here you go.
可以吗
Okay?
好
All right.
他情况很不妙
His condition is critical.
生命迹象不稳定
Vital signs unstable.
可能要上呼吸机
We may have to put him on a ventilator.
这得看情况
We'll see.
我们照了X光  你们之前说
We also did x-rays. Now, you told admitting
他接受了肝脏移植手术  对吗
that he'd had a liver transplant?
-是啊  -不是
- Yes. - No.
恐怕不是的
Afraid that's not true.
-什么  -肝还是那个肝
- What? - Same old liver in there.
但他的确经历了一场大手术
He has, however, undergone a major surgery.
他的肾被切除了一个
He's had a kidney removed.
他们竟然偷了他的肾
They stole his goddamn kidney?
不  不  不  不
No! No, no! No!
肝移植的切口应该是在这个位置
The incision for a liver transplant would be here.
但是弗兰克的切口
You may have noticed that Frank's incision
-在这儿  -天呐
- is down here. - Oh, god.
他能活多久
How long does he have?
不太确定  几天
No way to be sure, but... Days?
也可能是几小时
Maybe hours.
节哀
I'm sorry.
真对不起  弗兰克
Oh, I'm-- I am so sorry, Frank.
我们什么都试过了
We just-- we just tried everything.
弗兰克  我想求你件事
Frank, I-I have a favor to ask.
你知道我们本来应该在今天结婚吧
You know how we were supposed to be married today?
我知道  你现在可能没兴趣结婚
I know you're not feeling so hot,
目前的情况也和计划不同
and this isn't the setting we'd pictured,
但我想知道
But I was wondering if you would want
你肯在医院里娶我吗
to marry me here in the hospital.
要是你喜欢这主意
So, I don't know, if you like the idea,
就给我一点反应  好吗
Maybe you could give me a sign or something?
弗兰克
Frank?
Frank.
弗兰克
Oh, Frank.
你真是全世界最可爱的男人
You're the sweetest man in the whole world.
我去告诉大家
I'll let everyone know.
他说这是他梦寐以求的
He said he couldn't be more thrilled.
老天
Oh, my god.
我的天
Oh, my goodness.
什么
Yeah?
再给我点...  止痛药
More...Pills.
-我家住这里  -住超市里吗
- My family lives in there. - The supermarket?
-不是  -还好  住超市也太苦逼了
- No. - Oh, 'cause that would suck.
住在货车里面
In the van.
啊对  货车就很酷
Oh, yeah. That's cool. Van.
我们一天要搬两次家  因为如果车被拖走
We move it twice a day, 'cause if we get towed,
我们就完蛋了
We're screwed.
那是你的兄弟姐妹吗
Are those your brothers and sisters?
这里是四个  车上还有三个
Four of them. Three more in the van.
想见见他们吗
Wanna meet them?
好啊
Okay.
妈妈  这是卡尔
Oh. Mom. This is Carl.
我跟你说起过他
I told you about him.
-送糖的  -他们很喜欢那些糖
- The--the candy? - Oh. They love the candy.
说谢谢
Say thank you.
谢谢
Thank you.
我今天晚班  可能就在比利家睡了
I got the late shift, and I'll probably crash at Billy's.
钥匙在洁米那儿
Jamie's got the keys, okay?
走了
Bye.
想不想参观一下
So, you want a tour?
参观货车吗  好啊
Of the van? Yeah, okay.
等等
Wait. Hold on.
-怎么了  -我爸要死了
- What's wrong? - My dad's gonna die.
还要结婚了  你来吗
And he's getting married. Do you want to come?
好啊
Yeah.
你跟他好好聊聊
If you just talk to him,
肯定能解决问题的
I'm sure you could work something out.
是啊  他是要被解决一下
Yeah, he's gonna work something out,
依我的风格  就该用步枪
All right-- work it out with an AR-15 to his fucking head.
把这家伙的脑壳崩了
That's how I like to negotiate.
这他妈怎么回事
The fuck is this?
你们饿不饿
You guys hungry?
-算默认吗  -你还跟他一起干什么
- That a yes? - The fuck are you doing with him?
-吃午餐  -和这王八蛋
- Having lunch. - With this piece of shit?
你昨天还想要他的命
You wanted him dead yesterday.
别逗了
Psh, don't be dramatic.
曼迪  他打了你的脸
Mandy, he hit you. In the face.
他没有
No, he didn't.
-你确定  -他没有
- Seriously? - No, he didn't.
我昨天那么说只是因为我很生气
I just said that 'cause I was angry,
而且昨天喝多了  自己摔的
And I was shitfaced. I fell.
-你摔的  -行啊
- You fell. - Yeah, okay.
蠢脚丫子  好好享用你的狗屁意面吧
All right, then, clumsy feet. Enjoy your fucking spaghetti.
我带你走吧
I'm gonna get you out of here right now.
我保证会带你去安全的地方
I promised I was gonna get you someplace safe,
-离他远远的  好吗  -你松手
- Away from him, okay? - Hey, let go.
你忍不了这种事的  好吗
Listen, you can't stand for this, all right?
-松手  -你说过
- Let--let go! - You said you weren't gonna
你不想这样的
stand for this--come on!
曼迪
Mandy--
怎么回事
What the fuck?
别冲动  别冲动
Easy! Easy!
伊恩
Ian.
看着我
Look at me.
没事的
We're cool.
一切都没事
Everything's cool.
我们走吧
We're leaving. Let's go.
你他妈怎么回事
What the fuck's going on with you, huh?
刚才还像个超人一样
One minute, you're like superman,
到处跑  还做煎饼
Running around, making pancakes,
拍什么日出的鬼照片
taking pictures of the goddamn sunrise.
一回头你就要割别人的喉咙
The next thing, you wanna cut somebody's throat.
你是嗑药了还是怎么样
You smoking meth or something?
行啊  玩手机去吧
Yeah, please, check your phone.
我就当自己在跟墙嚷嚷
I'll just yell at the fucking wall.
弗兰克出事了
It's Frank.
给你
Here you go.
你没要吃的吗
You didn't get anything?
没有  我买了咖啡
Uh, no, I got coffee.
但拜托你吃点东西吧
Please eat something, though.
我知道  不用我告诉你
I know I don't need to tell you this,
你也知道自己看起来有多狼狈
but you look fucking terrible.
我不想成为另一个弗兰克或莫妮卡
I don't want to be another Frank or Monica.
-没人说你是  -我不是想让你鼓励我
- Nobody's saying that you are. - I'm not fishing for a pep talk.
我只是...
I just...
我都不认识我自己了
I don't know who I am anymore.
很明显  至少已经不是那个
I mean, since clearly I'm not the big sister
照顾全家的大姐了
taking care of everyone.
也许这是件好事
Maybe that's good.
好什么
How?
因为照顾我们不是你人生唯一的事
Well, 'cause there's more to you than that.
是啊  现在成了罪犯菲奥娜
Yeah. Fiona the criminal.
我是认真的
I'm serious.
你总是在背后支持我们
You know, you've always been there for us.
我们都把那当成是理所当然的事了
And I think we've taken it for granted.
至少我自己是这样的
You know, I know I have.
然后  你陷入了困境
And then you're going through some shit,
我却撒手不管
and I turn my back.
真是...
It's--
真是混账
It's bullshit.
对不起
I'm sorry.
小黛
Hey, Debs.
是的  她在车里
Yeah, she's in the car.
她在吃鸡蛋三明治
She's eating an egg sandwich.
-她还好吗  -她没事
- She's okay? - Yeah, she's fine.
-让她听电话  -好的
- Put her on. - Okay.
你好  小黛
Hi, Debs.
抱歉我让大家担心了
Sorry I freaked everyone out.
听见你的声音真好
Oh, it's so good to hear your voice.
我也一样
You too.
我马上回家了
I'm coming home.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
告诉利普  弗兰克快死了
Oh, and tell Lip that Frank's dying
还有  他要跟希拉结婚  所以
and getting married to Sheila, so we're going
我们要去医院  好吗
to the hospital, okay?
回家再见  小心开车
I'll see you at home. Drive safe.
什么...  好
Wha--o-okay.
再见
Bye.
我已经很努力  很努力了
I'm trying, I'm trying.
小维  那个不是应该先从手臂下面过去
V, V, isn't it supposed to go under the arm,
-再往上包的吗  -我不就是这么弄的吗
- and then over? - Isn't that what I just did?
-我不知道  -看护士弄起来
- I don't know. - The nurse made it look
那么简单
so easy.
但她动作太快
Yeah, but she did it so fast.
-所以我们才没学会  -好啦
- That's why we didn't learn it. - Okay.
再试一次  合作一点
Let's try it again. Work with me.
这次我会弄好的  我保证
I'm gonna get it right. I promise.
我明白  我懂
I know. I got it.
-我懂  -黛比发来的短信
- I got it. - Text from Debbie.
菲奥娜没事
Fiona's safe.
是吗  真的吗  快给我念念
She is? Really? Read it to me.
怎么写的
What does it say?
"菲奥娜没事"
"Fiona's safe."
也太简短了吧
Little short on detail.
那是什么
What is that?
你干什么
What are you doing?
没事
Everything's fine.
你们仨在这呆着  我会处理
You three just stay here. I got this.
-才不  -我马上回来
- Hell, no! - I'll be right back.
你从哪里搞来的  放回去  凯文
Where did you get that? Put that back. Kevin!
你们干什么
Hey, what are you doing?
我们需要安静
We need quiet here!
你们他妈的搞什么... 快滚
What the fuck are you-- get outta here!
小兔崽子们
Little assholes.
我靠  亲爱的
Holy fuck. Sweetheart?
告诉我  我没射中你们
Tell me I didn't shoot anyone.
我没有射中任何人  我们都没事对吗
I didn't shoot anyone, right? We're all okay?
-我操  -别靠近我和宝宝
- Holy fuck. - Do not come near my babies.
那是子弹孔吗
Is that a bullet hole?
-对不起  -凯文  我是认真的
- I am so sorry. - Kevin, I'm not kidding.
-我真的很对不起  -别靠近我
- I am so fucking sorry. - Do not come near me.
我发誓  我会把枪都处理掉  好吗
I swear, I'm gonna get rid of all the guns, okay?
对不起
I'm so sorry.
-不要枪  -不要枪
- No more guns? - No more guns.
不要枪了
No more guns.
上帝呀
Oh, god. Oh.
弗兰克  一切都还好吗
Hey, Frank, how's it going?
戴上
Put those on.
这会是个酷毙了的婚礼
Uh, it's gonna be a cool wedding.
恭喜  弗兰克不是已婚的吗
Congratulations. Hey, is Frank still married?
他和莫妮卡离婚了吗
Did him and Monica get a divorce?
管他的
Whatever.
我只是想说  我爱你
I just wanted to say that I love you.
以前的事都原谅你了
And that I forgive you for everything.
只要你别死
Unless you live.
然后...  我还是生你的气
And then-- and then I'm still pissed off.
我不知道什么很厉害的临终赠言
I don't really know any cool last words,
但是我希望你别死
but I don't want you to die,
我知道你也不想死
and I know you don't either.
所以  如果这真的是临终赠言
So if these are last words,
那就去他的吧
screw it.
说得好
I like that.
为了美满  每段婚姻
To succeed, every marriage
都必须经历许多困难
must surmount great obstacles--
只是通常没这么早
just usually not this early on.
但我们都知道
But as we now see,
成就一桩婚姻的
it is not the stained-glass windows
不是教堂一尘不染的窗户
of a church that make a wedding.
而是一对相爱的人
It is the two loving people
就站在  以及躺在我们面前
who stand--and lie-- before us.
抱歉
Excuse me.
我上次来的时候  还觉得
Last time I was here, I thought I was
自己跟其他人有天壤之别
so different from everyone else waiting.
穿着我的工作套装
In my office ensemble.
现在却跟他们一样了
Now I fit right in.
我知道你得学习
I know you have to study.
等出了结果我打给你
I'll call you when I know what's happening.
我在这里学就行
I can study here.
希拉  你愿意去爱护珍惜弗兰克
Sheila, do you promise to love and cherish Frank
无论病痛...
in sickness and--
我想病痛就够了
Uh, I guess just in sickness,
直到死亡将你们分离吗
Till death do you part?
我愿意
I do.
我们相信弗兰克一定也是这么想的
Uh, and we'll assume Frank feels the same.
-他是  -弗兰克和希拉
- He does. - Frank and Sheila,
在此  我宣布  你们成为
It is my honor to declare you
合法夫妻
man and wife.
你可以亲吻新郎了
You may kiss the groom.
让开  大家都让开
Move! I need everybody to move!
-退后  请让开  -退开  大家往后退
- Back up, please. Move away. - Step back. I need everyone to step back.
怎么了
What?
-让一让  -出什么事了
- Get out of the way. - What's going on?
从床边让开
Move away from the bed.
-他死了吗  -他情况危急
- Is he dead? - He's in serious condition,
所以我们把他挪到名单第一位了
so they moved him up the waiting list.
-那是什么意思  -他要得到一个新肝了
- What does that mean? - He's getting a liver.
什么
What?
那么
So.
你先自己说吧
You want to go first?